Let's get started with Day 8 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
This time, we're going to practice expressions about the comfort of wearing clothes.
Remember basic expressions such as tight and loose and use them in the sentence.
Okay, it's time for your first try.
S.P.R. Training
では日本語を時間内に英語で言ってみてください
最初の文に行く前に試着するを英語で言ってみよう
試着する
Try on
何々
を使います
ではそれを使ってこちらを言ってみよう
Can I try on this shirt?
Here you go.
Before we move on to the next sentence, let's say 試着室 in English.
Depending on the store, the fitting room is common.
Let's use the fitting room to say this.
Which is the fitting room?
How does it feel?
Let's check the answer here.
Let's use this sentence instead of the word, how does it feel?
How does it feel?
If you use the word, feel, while talking about clothes, you can express how you feel.
So, let's use the word, feel.
Kigo-gochi ga ii desu.
Dewa, tsugi desu.
Kitsui desuka?
Kotae wo iimasu.
Is it tight?
Yofuku nado ga kitsui to iitai toki ni tight o tsukaimasu.
Sa, tight o tsukaitte kochira wo itte miyo.
Sukoshi kitsuku kanjimasu.
Before we move on to the next sentence, let's say the opposite of tight, yurui, in English, please.
The answer is loose.
Let's use the word loose to say this.
Is it too loose?
It feels a little loose, but it's not too loose.
では、次の文に行く前に、この語彙を確認しましょう。
洋服が縮む。
How do you say 縮む in English?
The answer is shrink.
一回言ってみよう。
Shrink.
Good.
では、それを使ってこちらを言ってみよう。
このTシャツは縮みますか?
少し縮むかもしれません
OK, how was your first round?
Did you try to say each one?
ではここで回答例をチェックしましょう
OK, now you can check your answers with mine
And if you have our textbook
You can open it up and follow along
このシャツを試着してもいいですか?
Is it okay if I try on this shirt?
May I try on this shirt?
も伝わりますが、
Is it okay?
と聞くと、
このお店のルールとしては、
試着してもいいかどうか聞けます。
ですので、
Is it okay if...
さあ、一回ジェニーさんのあたりに行ってみよう。
Is it okay if I try on this shirt?
では、次です。試着室はどちらですか?
Where is the fitting room?
着心地はいかがですか?
How does it feel?
着心地がいいです。
It feels nice.
キツイですか?
Is it tight?
あるいは、 Does it feel tight? でも正解です。
次の文にfeelが入りますよ。
こちら。
少しきつく感じます。
It feels a little tight.
ゆるすぎますか?
Is it too loose?
少しゆるい感じがしますが、ゆるすぎではありません。
It feels a little loose, but not too loose.
このTシャツは縮みますか?
Will this T-shirt shrink?
日本語のTシャツは英語で言うと、
一枚ならTシャツ、単数形で表現します。
Will this T-shirt shrink?
一回ジェニーさんのあたりに行ってみよう。
では次です。
少し縮むかもしれません。
It might shrink a little.
Okay, did you understand today's phrases?
それでは皆さん、今学習した表現をテンポよくもう一度言ってみましょう。
We'll pick up the pace a little in round two.
Here we go!
このシャツを試着してもいいですか?
Is it okay if I try on this shirt?
試着室はどちらですか?
Where is the fitting room?
着心地はいかがですか?
How does it feel?
着心地がいいです。
It feels nice.
Kitsui desu ka?
Is it tight?
Sukoshi kitsuku kanjimasu.
It feels a little tight.
Yurusugi basu ka?
Is it too loose?
It feels a little loose, but not too loose.
Will this T-shirt shrink?
It might shrink a little.
Okay, time's up.
Well, how was your second try?
Today we talked about clothes.
How they feel, tight or loose, and whether they shrink.
Jenny, do your clothes shrink often?
Well, sometimes if I dry them in the dryer.
You have a dryer.
Jenny-san no uchi ni kansouki dryer ga arimasu.
Dryer to iu to daitai kansouki wo sashimasu ga,
kaminoki no dryer wa hair dryer to itta hou ga wakari yasui desu.
So you don't dry them outside.
I usually dry them in the dryer.
But if something might shrink, I usually dry it in the drying room.
You have a drying room? Oh, in the bathroom.
Yes, in the bathroom.
I can choose cold air to dry it, so then I know it won't shrink.
I see.
みなさんはいかがですか?
What do you do so your clothes don't shrink?
Okay, let's learn some useful phrases and have some good conversations.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
ekaewa time trial
bye bye